Matthew Machurek

Software Developer 615-828-7853 • matthew.machurek@yahoo.com LinkedIn • GitHub • Website

ABOUT ME

Prior to beginning my journey into software development I had risen through the ranks as a Graphic Designer starting as a production artist, moving to a team lead and finally a production manager. At that point I realized I had hit a wall in future growth and with some research I learned more about software development and became very interested and passionate about coding and development. As a software developer I can use my resources as a graphic designer to help me stand out more and give even more to a future employer. I feel all the years of graphic design and management experience has led me to be a unique asset as a software developer and I can't wait to enter into the field of software development.

SKILLS

Python

React

Django

CSS

HTML

Javascript

Photoshop

Illustrator

InDesign

EDUCATION

Certificate, Software Developer | Nashville Software School

Masters in History | American Public University System

Bachelor of Arts Degree in Graphic Art and Design | Nossi College of Art

Associate of Occupational Studies in Commercial Art | Nossi College of Art

DEVELOPMENT EXPERIENCE

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL • Junior Developer

A six month intense full-stack web developer apprenticeship that focuses on instructing junior developers with hands-on and group training.

- Build single page applications using HTML, CSS, Javascript and React
- Build server side applications using Python and Django
- Utilize third Party API's and Json server
- Version control with Git and Github
- Build ERD's with db diagram

Projects

History Traveler • Link

A website that has a database of historic landmarks of multiple cities where a user could sort through and add to itineraries. This was a Capstone project at NSS.

- Build single page application using HTML, CSS, Javascript and React
- Designed to be dynamic and component based where each component had a single responsibility
- Utilize Json server
- Version control with Git and Github

Matthew Machurek

Page Two of Two

Holiday Road • Link

A group project at NSS for a website that has a database of national parks so a user can select a park and activities around the park to experience. This was a group coding experience with shared time being the lead coder while other times spent researching documentation and fixing bugs.

- Created multiple modules, drop down menus and the logo for the application
- Build single page application using HTML, CSS and Javascript
- · Designed to be dynamic and component based where each component had a single responsibility
- Utilize third Party API's
- Version control with Git and Github

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

A2 ADVERTISING, 11.2013 - 09.2020

Production Manager Responsibilities:

- Directed a design team of up to 11 employess
- Worked on implementing project management software and automation software
- · Oversaw team productivity ensuring workload alignment with project objectives using Teamwork software(similar to Github)
- Functioned as the liaison between account coordinators and designers
- In charge of hiring new designers

Team Lead Responsibilities:

- Directed a design team of up to 3 employess
- Oversaw team productivity ensuring workload alignment with project objectives
- Functioned as the liaison between managers and designers
- · Worked on advertising for the more important clients using Adobe InDesign, Photoshop and Illustrator

Production Artist Responsibilities:

- Worked on multiple grocery stores and their newspaper and other advetisments using Adobe InDesign, Photoshop and Illustrator
- Fast paced intense environment
- Worked in a team atmosphere comuunicationg with co-workers whenever needed

HALO REALTY, 2.2011 - 9.2011

Graphic Designer Responsibilities:

- Created graphic materials for brochures, newspaper advertisements, business cards, post cards, etc. with Adobe Photoshop and Illustrator
- Filmed live auctions and edited them afterwards with IMovie
- Filmed footage for advertising
- Researched market trends and presented the data Microsoft Office

RE/MAX AUCTION DIVISION, 9.2009 - 2.2011

Graphic Designer Responsibilities:

 Created graphic materials for brochures, newspaper advertisements and other misc. advertisements with Adobe Photoshop and Illustrator